imathlete.com 2014-05-03

# Privacy Policy | imATHLETE

#### The Basics

We strive to maintain your privacy in all matters. If we gather information we want you to know when and how. That's the point of this. Suffice to say, we hate spam as much as the next guy, so to save you from reading through this whole thing just to find out what we do with your email address, let me tell you right now that we treasure your privacy and do not sell the imATHLETE membership list. If you have opted to become an imATHLETE member, you will receive some limited communication from us. You can opt-out at anytime. If you have used imATHLETE to register for an event or club or other type of activity ("Activity"), the organizer of that Activity ("Organizer") has the right to contact you at their sole discretion, without imATHLETE's approval. It is in our agreement with the Organizer that they "will be responsible for protecting the privacy and security of any information that [they] retrieve." 

It is our intention not to do business with recognized spammers. As mentioned, we treasure your privacy and are pretty sure that you already get enough emails about vi@gr@ and cheap mortgages that you don't want us to contribute to that annoyance anymore than we want to be part of it. 

If you just browse around the imATHLETE website, no information is collected other than that which is typically collected in server logs by any given website you visit. We may plant cookies for your convenience. 

If you contribute to imATHLETE by adding or editing information, you are publishing all of the words and information that you post. You should assume that everything you put on the Website will be there forever, because it might be in an Internet archive somewhere. 

#### Publishing information on imATHLETE

Your identity will not be publicly exposed by just visiting the imATHLETE website. When you add or edit a page, this is considered to be "publishing". "Publishing" is a public act. WHENEVER YOU PUBLISH INFORMATION ON IMATHLETE, YOU ARE ALWAYS PUBLICLY IDENTIFIED AS THE AUTHOR OF THAT INFORMATION. 

#### Identification of an author

It is required that you be logged-in to an account for you to Publish information. Since you are logged-in to an account when you Publish information, you will be identified by the user name of the account. The user name will be your real name, as identified when you initially created the account. The account username will be the identifying name for information you Publish. 

Additionally, any information you Publish may also be tracked by your network IP address, Your IP address will not be readily available to the public. Instead, your IP address may be stored in the imATHLETE servers and can be seen by our server administration folks and others who are granted individual and temporary access. 

In case you don't know, an IP address is a series of numbers that identifies the Internet address that you are using to access imATHLETE. Depending on your Internet connection, this IP number may be traceable to your home, school, office or just to your Internet service provider. You need to know that it is possible that the IP address may also be associated with other interests or websites you have visited on the Internet. It may or may not be difficult for somebody to connect your IP address with your actual identity. 

#### Cookies. Not chocolate chip.

imATHLETE may set a temporary cookie whenever you visit the site. Please note that you need this cookie to be able to log-in. If you deny this cookie, you won't be able to log-in to your account. Either way, the cookie will be deleted when you close your browser. 

When you log in to an account, we may set more cookies so that you don't have to keep typing in your username every time you visit this wonderful Website. Feel free to clear these cookies after you use the Website – especially if you are using a public machine and you don't want others to see your username. (While you're at it, you oughta clear the browser cache as well, just for safe keeping.) 

#### Passwords

All users are encouraged to select strong passwords and to never share them. As a basic rule, we highly suggest that you never let anybody know your passwords, Ever. We here at imATHLETE promise to never ask you for your password (except in a login box to gain access to certain parts of the Website) nor knowingly expose any user's password to another user or to the public, either directly or indirectly. We wouldn't want you to do that to us, so we're not going to do it to you. 

#### Private logging

Whether you know it or not, whenever you visit any web page on the Internet there is quite a bit of information that gets sent to the web servers. Most of this stuff is used simply to get an understanding of what pages are popular, what other sites link to that one and what web browsers people are using. Like most other websites, we here at imATHLETE will be gathering the same information as well. The only way we will be using this information is to create our site statistics (the log data is kept private and not made public.) No individual data is logged by our Website, except to maintain usernames and password lists and in some cases to track abuses and abusers. 

#### Abuse

From time to time we may look at individual IP addresses of users to try and correlate such addresses and usernames with abuse of the imATHLETE site. We don't like people who abuse our site and will do whatever is within our means to keep the abusers away and maintain your privacy. 

#### The Reasons We May Release Personal Data

There are a few instances in which we may release personal data of imATHLETE users. These instances are as follows: 

  1. In response to a subpoena or other compulsory request from law enforcement.
  2. With the permission of the user in question.
  3. When needed for investigation of abuse complaints. 
  4. When the information is needed to resolve technical issues. 
  5. Where it is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of the imATHLETE, its users, or the public. 

The imATHLETE Privacy Policy does not permit the public distribution of personal data for any reason, except as described above. 

#### The Sharing of User Information

Except where otherwise noted, all of the text that has been added to imATHLETE is available for reuse based on the Limited License agreement we have outlined in the imATHLETE Terms of Use and Dislaimer. 

imATHLETE will not sell or share private information (like e-mail addresses) to third parties unless you agree to release this information or we are required by law to release the info. 

#### Information Security

We have to tell you that imATHLETE makes no guarantee against unauthorized access to your information. Though we strive to create a highly secure environment, user information may be available to certain employees, internal developers, and administrators who have access to the imATHLETE servers. 

#### E-Mails

You may be asked to provide your e-mail address when you create a user account. Other logged-in users may send you e-mail through the imATHLETE system. Please not that your actual e-mail address will not be revealed to the other users unless you respond to them (or, perhaps, if the e-mail bounces). 

If you have opted-in to receive information from imATHLETE, we may use your e-mail address to communicate with you. In this case your e-mail address will be included on the imATHLETE mailing list, though the actual address will not be viewable to any other members. 

If you do not provide an accurate e-mail address, you will not be able to reset your password if you forget it. 

#### User data

Basic data on imATHLETE users, such as the number of edits they've made and the times at which they've edited information, may be available for other users to view. This information will not include e-mail addresses but, rather only usernames and/or IP addresses. 

#### Removal of user accounts

Once you've created a user account it can not be removed. You may change your user name if you really want to, though we can't guarantee that the username you want hasn't already been taken. 

#### Deletion of content

Removing information from an imATHLETE post does not permanently delete the information. Any person browsing the imATHLETE Website can view information that has been deleted. The only way information will be permanently deleted from the servers is if select administrators deem it necessary to remove the information. Unless there is a legal reason to remove information, this probably won't happen. 

That is our Privacy Policy. We hope you enjoyed reading it and we hope that it answered all of your questions. If you still have questions about your privacy, please feel free to drop us a line. 

If you don't have any questions, why not go outside and play. 

**Woohoo , ! You've connected with Facebook!**

### Do you already have an imATHLETE account?

Nope - Sign me up!  
Create an account and open up your world endurance sports. 

I already have one!  
Connect your imATHLETE account to Facebook in seconds.
